Govind S Kumar

Devops Engineer

+91 8848572227
☑ govindskumar22@gmail.com
in www.linkedin.com/in/govind-s-kumar
SKILLS
AWS
Kubernetes
Lauldes
Jenkins
Docker
Terraform
- Ciralettii
Ansible
Groovy
Shall Scripting
Shell Scripting
Python
Linux
0.17
GIT
Grafana
Adaptability
Adaptability
Communication

SUMMARY

Proven success in the field with more than 5 years of work experience in AWS, Jenkins, Kubernetes technologies along with knowledge in scripting tools like Terraform, Ansible & Groovy . Excellent team member, well versed in mapping client requirements and skilled in debugging issues and troubleshooting. Looking forward to effectively utilize my skills & knowledge to achieve company's goals and grow as a Cloud/ Devops engineer.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2018 - Present Devops Engineer

Standard Chartered GBS

- Implements and manages CI/CD pipelines using scripted pipelines in Jenkins.
- Helps migrate the existing Jenkins setup to multimaster highly available containerized setup on Kubernetes.
- Builds and maintains highly available systems on Kubernetes.
- Good experience in containerizing applications using Docker and writing Dockerfiles.
- Experience in building and monitoring solutions on AWS EC2, IAM, EBS, EFS VPC, S3, Cloudwatch etc.
- Experience in writing Terraform and Ansible scripts to provision and manage resources on AWS cloud.
- Experience in administering and managing JFROG artifactory service.
- Implemented artifactory archival and various management tasks using AQL and JFROG REST APIs in groovy.
- Experience in developing and maintains pipeline shared libraries using Groovy for use across the organization.
- Automating system management and housekeeping tasks using Shell scripts and Python.
- Good knowledge of GIT version control tool.
- Experienced in bitbucket project level administration and monitoring.
- Know-how and experience on creating monitoring dashboards and other visualisation activities on Grafana.

2017 - 2018 Senior Configuration Analyst

Standard Chartered GBS

- Migrated around 1000 apps from legacy build and release services to CI/CD automation using Jenkins.
- $\bullet\,$ Helped migrate all the release artefacts to JFROG artifactory.
- Wrote basic playbooks for Jenkins, Artifactory and Bitbucket server maintenance and deployments

2016 - 2017 Configuration Analyst

Standard Chartered GBS

- Implemented and managed Jenkins on onpremise servers.
- Wrote shell scripts to automate server maintenance and housekeeping.
- Wrote build configuration files for Maven, NPM, Docker builds.
- Helped deploy applications on premise servers using Ansible.

CERTIFICATIONS

 AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate Validation ID: E8C1FF8BJFB4133Y

Teamwork

PROJECTS

- SCM for the whole of Standard Chartered GBS
- VX Central Devops project for all the other projects.

LANGUAGES

English, Malayalam, Tamil, Hindi

• AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner Validation ID : J5YLP3TDDMV1QEGK

EDUCATION

2012 - 2016 Bachelor of Technology

Federal Institute of Science And Technology

Bachelor of Technology